{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Which Wildlife Sanctuary of Assam boasts of the golden langur",
        "options": [
          "A. Pani Dihing",
          "B. Pobitora",
          "C. Laokhowa",
          "D. Chakrashila"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Chakrashila"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one was the first capital of Ahom Kingdom in Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. Garhgaon",
          "B. Charaideo",
          "C. Jorhat",
          "D. Sivsagar"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Charaideo"
      },
      {
        "question": "The area of Kaziranga National Park is approximately",
        "options": [
          "A. 430 sq. km",
          "B. 500 sq. km",
          "C. 390 sq. km",
          "D. 720 sq. km"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 430 sq. km"
      },
      {
        "question": "About 91% of world population of a particular animal species found in Kaziranga National Park is which one of the following",
        "options": [
          "A. Asian hog deer",
          "B. Pygmy hog",
          "C. Asiatic wild buffalo",
          "D. Sangai deer"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Pygmy hog"
      },
      {
        "question": "Of the total production of Muga, the Golden Silk, in the world, Assam produces",
        "options": [
          "A. 69%",
          "B. 79%",
          "C. 89%",
          "D. 99%"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 99%"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which of the following National Parks/Wildlife Sanctuaries, the density of rhino population is the highest",
        "options": [
          "A. Manas",
          "B. Kaziranga",
          "C. Pobitora",
          "D. Nameri"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Pobitora"
      },
      {
        "question": "The highest concentration of forest in the State of Assam occurs in",
        "options": [
          "A. Karbi Anglong district",
          "B. Dima Hasao district",
          "C. Goalpara district",
          "D. Dhubri district"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Karbi Anglong district"
      },
      {
        "question": "Pani Dihing Bird Sanctuary is located in which one of the following districts",
        "options": [
          "A. Jorhat",
          "B. Sivasagar",
          "C. Golaghat",
          "D. Dhemaji"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Sivasagar"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the first martyr of 1942 Revolution in Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. Kanaklata Barua",
          "B. Kamala Miri",
          "C. Kushal Konwar",
          "D. Maniram Dewan"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Kanaklata Barua"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Treaty of Yandaboo signed between East India Company and which one of the following",
        "options": [
          "A. Ahom King",
          "B. King of Burma",
          "C. Kachari King",
          "D. Chutiya King"
        ],
        "answer": "B. King of Burma"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first Peasant Uprising against the British was known as",
        "options": [
          "A. Phulaguri Dhawa",
          "B. Patharughat Raijmel",
          "C. Battle of Itakhuli",
          "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Phulaguri Dhawa"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first phase of Moamoria Rebellion was started in",
        "options": [
          "A. 1749",
          "B. 1759",
          "C. 1769",
          "D. 1779"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1769"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which year Gopinath Bordoloi was arrested for taking part in the freedom movement",
        "options": [
          "A. 1915",
          "B. 1918",
          "C. 1920",
          "D. 1922"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 1922"
      },
      {
        "question": "In addition to Assamese, which other language from the State is included in the Eight Schedule of the Indian Constitution",
        "options": [
          "A. Mishing",
          "B. Rabha",
          "C. Tiwa",
          "D. Bodo"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Bodo"
      },
      {
        "question": "The rank of Assam in literacy among the States of India is",
        "options": [
          "A. 9th",
          "B. 12th",
          "C. 16th",
          "D. 26th"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 26th"
      }
    ]
  }
  